Aiko Klostermann

2 Marina Blvd #30-06 Singapore 018987 (a) +65 845 77 420 / +49 176 2746 9084 ⊠ jobs@aiko.dev

nttps://aiko.dev

in aikoklostermann

Senior Software Engineer

Summary

I have worked in multiple microservice/distributed system architectures with several different technology stacks and have untilized numerous different architectural patterns.

Additionally I share my ideas and learnings by giving (keynote)talks and workshops at international conferences and writing articles which have been published by multiple publications.

Experience

Grab Taxi Holding

3/2021 - 08/2021 Senior Software Engineer, Singapore.

Golang, gRPC, • Building Testing Automation Framework and Platform for all Grab Engineers

AWS, Bash • Being service owner of multiple services and managing direct report

ThoughtWorks

• Building high quality, maintainable, scalable, robust and fault-tolerant software for various clients applying best practices like TDD, DDD, CI/CD, IaC, Pair Programming

5/2019 - 2/2021 Senior Software Engineer, mostly Singapore.

Java, Python, • Led platform-wide performance testing and optimization effort(scale: >10 billion db rows)

Typescript, • Took over the tech lead role of the team at the final stages of a project

Node.js, AWS, • Introduced client team to infrastructure as code(IaC)

Kubernetes

Azure, Docker, Onboarded multiple batches of new hires by giving lectures on topics like Clean Code design concepts like SOLID principles, Pair Programming, TDD, etc.

• Organised and facilitated a weekly infrastructure engineering study group

6/2017 - 4/2019 Software Engineer, mostly Bangalore, India.

Java, Python, • Introduced the client to the concept of CI and importance of a comprehensive test coverage

Docker

Django, AWS, o Joined a project with nearing deadline due to of my expertise in Python which led to us delivering ahead of time after all

• Led the Data/AI/ML enthusiasts group in ThoughtWorks India with > 130 members

6/2016 - 5/2017 Graduate Software Engineer, Hamburg, Germany.

Java, Python, • Introduced client to neural networks & increased order prediction accuracy by 18% to 82%

AWS, Tensorflow Owned cloud migration effort and managed to be the first team to go-live on cloud infrastructure University of Applied Sciences Hamburg

3/2014 - 8/2014 Teaching Assistant for Programming II, Hamburg, Germany.

Taught advanced Java/Programming concepts including Multithreading, Generics and Inner classes

Additional Achievments

• (Keynote)Speaker at various international conferences

• Have had my articles published by DataQuest, FinTechNews, Thoughtworks.com i.a.

• PROMOS Scholarship recipient for overall academic results

Education

9/2012 - 5/2016 University of Applied Sciences Hamburg, B.Sc. Computer Science.

Thesis Project: Convolutional Neural Networks on Mobile Devices Grade: 4.0/4.0

8/2014 - 12/2014 The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Semester Abroad.

Languages Java, Python, Javascript & Typescript, Golang, C, C++, HTML, CSS, HCL

Frameworks Spring {Boot}, Django, Flask, Node.js, React, ReactNative, Angular, TensorFlow

DevOps/Infra Terraform, Cloudformation, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux/Unix Shells, Ansible, AWS, Azure

Others PostgreSQL, MongoDb, REST, GraphQL, gRPC, Protobuf, Apache Kafka, distributed sys-

tems/microservice architecture, Jupyter Notebook, TDD, Performance optimization